A Guide to the Lester M. Salamon Papers FA1868
Rockefeller Archive Center
Lester M. Salamon papers
1964-2022
Rockefeller Archive Center
Lester M. Salamon (1943-2021)
FA1868
63.54 Cubic Feet 155 containers, 4 framed items.
1.6 Gigabytes
Arrangement
The Lester M. Salamon papers are arranged into the following series:
Series 1: Writings
Series 2: Speeches and Presentations
Series 3: Books
Series 4: Reference Material
Series 5: Course Material
Series 6: Philanthropication thru Privatization (PtP) Project
Series 7: Pilot Projects
Series 8: Related Projects
Series 9: Photographs
Series 10: Oversize Framed Material
Scope and Contents
The Lester M. Salamon papers contain drafts, publications, presentations, books, project materials, correspondence, and photographs. Most of the material pertains to Salamon's articles and books. There are many drafts in the collection, with versions written and edited by Salamon. Additionally, there is course material from Johns Hopkins University, project files, and documentation of various conferences and trips. Despite Lester Salamon being a board member of the International Society for Third-Sector Research (ISTR), there are only a few files related to his time there.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. Access copy currently unavailable. Please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Lester M. Salamon papers were donated to the RAC by his wife Lynda Salamon in 2022.
Privatization; Voluntarism; Economic development; Philanthropy -- Case studies; Charity laws and legislation
- Writings, 1969-2022; 1; 27.62 Cubic Feet (72 containers)
  Scope and Contents
  The Writings series contains poems, journal articles, drafts of book chapters, and material related to the many publications written by Lester Salamon. Copies of published books can be found in the "Books" series.
  - International Guide to Nonprofit Law, 1969-2001; 1
    - International Guide to Nonprofit Law, Lester M. Salamon, Wiley & Sons, Inc., 1997 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1993-1997 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Promotion Materials, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Author's Questionnaire, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Index Manuscripts, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
    - Contracts, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
    - Contracts - Nina Belyaeva, 1990-1995 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Mott Foundation, 1997-2001 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Karla Simon, Poland, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Tom Silk Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Preface, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Chapter 1: Introduction, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Chapter 2: Nonprofit Law: Ten Issues in Search of Resolution - Corrections, 1995-1997 (Box 3, Folder 15-17)
    - Chapter 2: Nonprofit Law: Ten Issues in Search of Resolution - Flaherty, Draft 2, Second Part, 1995 October (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Various Drafts, Chapters 1-3, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 19-21)
    - Australia - Stefan's Revised Draft, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Australia - Correspondence/Comments, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Australia - Field Guide, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Brazil - Correspondence/Comments, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Brazil - LMS Revisions, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Canada - General National Information, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Canada - Blake Bromley, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Canada - Correspondence/Comments, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Canada - Field Guide, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Canada - LMS Revisions, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Egypt - Author's Comments, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Egypt - LMS Revisions, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Egypt - Stefan's Revised Draft, undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - France - General, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - France - Field Guide, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - France - Author's Comments, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - France - LMS Revisions, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - France - Stefan's Revised Draft, undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Germany - General, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Germany - Author's Comments, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Germany - Correspondence/Comments, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Ghana - General, 1993-1995 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - India - Field Guide, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Ireland - General, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Ireland - Author's Comments, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Ireland - Correspondence/Comments, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Ireland - Final Version, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Ireland - LMS Revisions, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Ireland - Stefan's Revised Draft, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Israel - Hadara Bar-Mor, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Israel - Correspondence/Comments, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Israel - LMS Revisions, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Japan - Author's Comments, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Japan - Correspondence/Comments, 1994-1997 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Mexico - General, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Mexico - Field Guide, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Netherlands - Author's Comments, undated (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - Netherlands - Correspondence/Comments, 1994-1996 (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - Netherlands - Field Guide, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - Netherlands - LMS Revisions, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - Poland - General, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - Poland - Correspondence/Comments, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - Poland - Stefan's Revised Draft, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - Russia - Correspondence/Comments, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - Russia - Field Guide, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 66)
    - Russia - Stefan's Revised Draft, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 67)
    - South Africa - General, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 68)
    - South Africa - Correspondence/Comments, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 69)
    - South Africa - Author's Comments, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 70)
    - South Africa - Field Guide, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 71)
    - South Africa - LMS Revisions, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 72)
    - South Africa - Stefan's Revised Draft, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 73)
    - Spain - Author's Comments, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 74)
    - Spain - Correspondence/Comments, 1995-1997 (Box 6, Folder 75)
    - Spain - Field Guide, undated (Box 6, Folder 76)
    - Spain - Final Version, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 77)
    - Spain - LMS Revisions, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 78)
    - Spain - Stefan's Revised Draft, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 79)
    - Sweden - Author's Comments, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 80)
    - Sweden - Correspondence/Comments, 1995-1997 (Box 7, Folder 81)
    - Sweden - Field Guide, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 82)
    - Sweden - Final Version, 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 83)
    - Sweden - LMS Revisions, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 84)
    - Sweden - Stefan's Revised Draft, undated (Box 7, Folder 85)
    - Tanzania - General, 1996-1998 (Box 7, Folder 86)
    - Thailand - Correspondence/Comments, 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 87)
    - Thailand - Author's Comments, 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 88)
    - Thailand - Field Guide, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 89)
    - Thailand - Final Version, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 90)
    - Thailand - LMS Revisions, 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 91)
    - Thailand - Stefan's Revised Draft, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 92)
    - United Kingdom - General, undated (Box 7, Folder 93)
    - United Kingdom - Author's Comments, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 94)
    - United Kingdom - Correspondence/Comments, 1969-1997 (Box 8, Folder 95)
    - United Kingdom - LMS Revisions, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 96)
    - United Kingdom - Stefan's Revised Draft, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 97)
    - United States - Correspondence/Comments, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 98)
    - United States - Author's Comments, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 99)
    - United States - LMS Revisions, undated (Box 8, Folder 100)
    - United States - Stefan's Revised Draft, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 101)
  - South Asian Conference on Laws, Rules, Regulations for the Voluntary Sector, New Delhi, India, 1996 March 6-10; 2
    - Country Paper - Pakistan, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 102)
    - Country Paper - Bangladesh, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 103)
    - Summary of Country Reports, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 104)
    - Country Paper - Nepal - NGOs Bewildered: The Nepalese Case, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 105)
    - Country Paper - Sri Lanka, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 106)
  - Tools - General, 1980-2021; 3
    Variations of writings and workshops on "New Governance and Tools of Public Action" and related topics.
    - The New Governance and Tools of Public Action: An Introduction, 2001 (Box 58, Folder 519)
    - The Nonprofit Sector and the Tools of Government: An Exploratory Analysis, 2001 (Box 58, Folder 520)
    - The Tools Approach: A New Perspective of Government Perspective, undated (Box 58, Folder 521)
    - Follow-up Group, Grants Workshop, 2004 (Box 59, Folder 522)
    - Federal Grants, Tim Conlan, 2004 (Box 59, Folder 523)
    - Conference on Policy Tools and Government Performance, 2002 (Box 59, Folder 524)
    - The New Governance: A Paradigm for the New Milennium, 2000-2001 (Box 59, Folder 525)
    - The New Governance and Tools of Public Action: Implications for China, 2009 (Box 59, Folder 526)
    - Tools Handbook - Chapter 1, 2001 (Box 59, Folder 527)
    - Conclusion, 2001 (Box 59, Folder 528)
    - Canada VSI Conference, 2006 (Box 59, Folder 529)
    - Tools of Government Handbook - The Tools Approach and the New Governance: Conclusions and Implications - Copyedited Chapter, 2001 (Box 59, Folder 530)
    - Tools of Government Handbook - The Tools Approach and the New Governance: Conclusions and Implications - Oxford Version, 2001 (Box 59, Folder 531)
    - The New Governance and the Tools of Public Actions: An Introduction, Urban Law Journal - Final Edits, 2001 (Box 59, Folder 532)
    - Tools of Government: A Public Management Handbook for the Era of Third-Party Government, 1999-2000 (Box 59, Folder 533)
    - The New Governance and the Tools of Public Action: An Introduction - Fordham Edited Version, 2001 (Box 59, Folder 534)
    - Introductory Chapter - Comments, 2000 (Box 60, Folder 535)
    - Chapter 22 - The Tools Approach and the New Governance: Conclusions and Implications, undated (Box 60, Folder 536)
    - Governance: Special Issues on Policy Instruments, 2004 (Box 60, Folder 537)
    - Third-Party Government: The New Normal in Government and Nonprofit Operations - Encyclopedia, undated (Box 60, Folder 538)
    - Tax Expenditure Briefing Book, 2007 (Box 60, Folder 539)
    - Contracting Briefing Book, 2007 (Box 60, Folder 540)
    - The New Governance and the Tools of Public Action: Implications for Canada, 2009 (Box 60, Folder 541)
    - Lombardy Region Government, 2009 (Box 60, Folder 542)
    - Training Professional Citizens, Keynote, National Association of Schools of Public Affairs and Administration (NASPAA), 2004 (Box 60, Folder 543)
    - Lombardy Models of Government, 2011 (Box 60, Folder 544)
    - Lombardy Assessment Project, 2010 (Box 60, Folder 545)
    - The New Governance and the Changing Tools of Public and Private Actions, Canada Presentation, 2012 (Box 60, Folder 546)
    - Tools Book Intro Miscellaneous Material, undated (Box 60, Folder 547)
    - Tools Handbook Drafts, 2000 (Box 60, Folder 548)
    - Pier Mario Vello - Generosity, 2009 (Box 60, Folder 549)
    - The Tools of Government - Final Version, 2000 (Box 77, Folder 799-800)
    - The Tools of Government - Notes, 2000 (Box 77, Folder 801)
    - The Tools of Government: A Public Management Handbook for the Era of Third-Party Government - Draft, 1998-1999 (Box 83, Folder 837-840)
    - Tools Handbook Chapters, Volume 3, 1999 (Box 91, Folder 883-884)
    - The Tools of Government - Chapter Authors Conference, 1999 (Box 94, Folder 901-905)
    - Tools Readings, 1994-1995 (Box 96, Folder 911-912)
    - Types of Tools, 1980-1993 (Box 134, Folder 1496)
    - Second Edition Articles, 2020-2021 (Box 134, Folder 1497)
    - Second Edition Resources, 2001-2009 (Box 134, Folder 1498)
    - Survey Data, Chicago, 1982-1985 (Box 135, Folder 1499)
    - Northeast Local Survey Data, 1982-1985 (Box 135, Folder 1500)
    - Funding, PC Tables Survey Data, 1983 (Box 135, Folder 1501)
    - Working File, 1999-2000 (Box 135, Folder 1502)
    - Joseph Cordes, 2000 (Box 135, Folder 1503)
    - Ruth DeHoog, 2000 (Box 135, Folder 1504)
    - Don Kettl, 2000 (Box 135, Folder 1505)
    - Ron Feldman, 1999-2000 (Box 135, Folder 1506)
    - David Beam, Timothy Conlan, 1999-2000 (Box 135, Folder 1507)
    - Chris Howard, 2000 (Box 135, Folder 1508)
    - Kelman Contracting Chapter, 2000 (Box 135, Folder 1509)
    - Chris Lehman, 1999-2000 (Box 135, Folder 1510)
    - John Lordan, 1999-2000 (Box 135, Folder 1511)
    - Peter May, 199-2000 (Box 136, Folder 1512)
    - Roger Noll, 1999-2000 (Box 136, Folder 1513-1514)
    - Guy Peters, 2000 (Box 136, Folder 1515)
    - Paul Posner, 1999-2000 (Box 136, Folder 1516)
    - Arthur Ringeling, 2000 (Box 137, Folder 1517-1518)
    - Peter Schuck, 2000 (Box 137, Folder 1519)
    - Steve Smith, Helen Ingram, 2000 (Box 137, Folder 1520)
    - Tom Stanton, 2000 (Box 137, Folder 1521-1522)
    - C. Eugene Steuerle, Eric C. Twombly, 1999-2000 (Box 138, Folder 1523-1524)
    - Janet A. Weiss, 2000 (Box 138, Folder 1525)
  - Tools of Government Action, 1979-2022; 4
    Contains material related to the published book "Tools of Government Action" and the 1984 Tools of Government Action conference.
    - Conference - Participants, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 273)
    - Conference - Letters from Participants, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 274)
    - Conference - Processes of U.S. Federal Budgeting: A Framework for Analysis and Its Application to Budgeting for Credit Programs, Abramson, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 275)
    - Conference - Robert Coakley, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 276)
    - Eugene Bardach, 1985-1988 (Box 35, Folder 277)
    - Beyond Privatization: The Tools of Government Action, 1989 (Box 35, Folder 278)
    - The Changing Technology of Public Action, undated (Box 35, Folder 279)
    - Lund Bibliography, undated (Box 35, Folder 280)
    - Lund, Michael - Loan Guarantees, 1988 (Box 35, Folder 281)
    - Conference - Commercial Activities in Human Service Organizations, DeVita, Salamon, 1987 (Box 35, Folder 282)
    - Conference - Erwin Hargrove, 1984-1988 (Box 35, Folder 283)
    - Grants as a Tool of Public Policy, Donald Haider, 1984-1988 (Box 36, Folder 284)
    - Memoranda, 1984-1986 (Box 36, Folder 285)
    - Proofed Chapters - Introduction, Chapter 1: The Changing Technology of Public Action, Salamon, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 286)
    - Proofed Chapters - Chapter 2: The Tools Approach: Basic Analytics, Lund, Salamon, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 287)
    - Proofed Chapters - Chapter 3: The Forgotten Fundamental: Successes and Excesses of Direct Government, Christopher K. Leman, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 288)
    - Proofed Chapters - Chapter 4: Grants As A Tool of Public Policy, Donald Haider, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 289)
    - Proofed Chapters - Chapter 5: Between Welfare and the Market: Loan Guarantees as a Policy Tool, Michael S. Lund, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 290)
    - Proofed Chapters - Chapter 6: Tax Expenditures as Tools of Government Action, Paul R. McDaniel, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 291)
    - Proofed Chapters - Chapter 7: Social Regulations as a Generic Policy Implement, Eugene Bardach, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 292)
    - Proofed Chapters - Chapter 8: The Government-Corporation Tool: Permutations and Possibilities, Llyod Musolf, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 293)
    - Proofed Chapters - Chapter 9: Conclusion: Beyond Privatization, Salamon, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 294)
    - Basic Concepts, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 295)
    - Conference - Workshop Letters of Agreement, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 296)
    - Conference - Invitees, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 297)
    - Conference - Barry Mitnick, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 298)
    - Conference - Lawrence Revzan, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 299)
    - Conference - David Beam, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 300)
    - Conference - Regina Herzlinger, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 301)
    - Conference - Harvey Sapolsky, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 302)
    - Conference - Kent Weaver, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 303)
    - Conference - The "Tools" Perspective on Government Action: Purpose, Promise, and Tasks, Discussion Paper, Lund, Salamon, 1985 (Box 37, Folder 304)
    - Conference - General, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 305)
    - Conference - Workshop Materials, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 306)
    - Conference - Food/Housing, 1984 (Box 38, Folder 307)
    - Conference - Expense Requests, 1984-1985 (Box 38, Folder 308)
    - Conference - Contract, undated (Box 38, Folder 309)
    - Conference - Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, 1984 (Box 38, Folder 310)
    - Early Drafts, 1984 (Box 38, Folder 311-313)
    - Final Copy, undated (Box 38, Folder 314-316)
    - Author Questionnaire, 1988 (Box 39, Folder 317)
    - Policy Analysis as the Study of Implements, Richard E. Filmore, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 318)
    - Work Outline, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 319)
    - Donald Haider Paper Comments, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 320)
    - Suggestions for Coakley Paper, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 321)
    - McDaniel Tax Expenditures, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 322)
    - Coprovision: Citizen Time and Money Donations in Public Service Provision, James M. Ferris, 1984-1985 (Box 39, Folder 323)
    - A Managerial Analysis of Federal Income Redistribution Mechanisms, Herzlinger and Kane, 1979 (Box 39, Folder 324)
    - Competitive and Equitable Public Sector Conference, St. Paul, MN, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 325)
    - Comments on Musolf Paper, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 326)
    - Loan Guarantees, Lund, 1987 (Box 39, Folder 327)
    - McDaniel Revisions, 1986 (Box 39, Folder 328)
    - Direct Government, Chris Leman, 1984-1986 (Box 39, Folder 329)
    - Gene Bardach Social Regulation Paper, 1985-1986 (Box 39, Folder 330)
    - Government Corporations, Musolf, undated (Box 39, Folder 331)
    - Year 2 Proposal, 1984 (Box 40, Folder 332)
    - General, 1979-1985 (Box 40, Folder 333-338, Box 41, Folder 339-341)
    - National Science Foundation Proposal, 1983-1984 (Box 42, Folder 353)
    - Contacts, 1984-1985 (Box 42, Folder 354)
    - 20th Century Fund Proposal, 1984-1985 (Box 43, Folder 356)
    - The Changing Technology of Government Action Outline, 1984 (Box 43, Folder 357)
    - Privatization, 1980-1987 (Box 43, Folder 358-359)
    - The Tools of Government, 2nd Edition - Readings, Notes, and Drafts, 2011-2022 (Box 88, Folder 871)
    - Tools of Government - Revision, 2020-2021 (Box 133, Folder 1481)
  - Local Development Study - Briefing, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 107)
  - Loan and Loan Guarantee Programs, 1977-1981 (Box 9, Folder 108-112)
  - Loan and Loan Guarantee Programs, 1974-1980 (Box 10, Folder 113-114)
  - Poems - Christmas, "Welcome Ye Somber Richardson", 1990 (Box 10, Folder 115)
  - Poems - Miscellaneous, 1988; undated (Box 10, Folder 116)
  - Poems - The Seven Christmases at Hopkins, undated (Box 101, Folder 950)
  - Mayland after the Recession: Plenty of Reasons to Worry, The Baltimore Sun, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 117)
  - Struttura e Finanziamento del Nonprofit Sector Negli U.S.A.: Implicazioni in Camp Artistico, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 118-119)
  - El Sector No Lucrativo en Los Estados Unidos de América: Una Introducción, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 120)
  - The Future of the Industrial City: The Challenges of Economic Change in America and Europe, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 121)
  - Reorganization Study of Local Development Assistance Programs, 1977-1980 (Box 10, Folder 122)
  - Maryland and the New World Economy: Challenges and Opportunities, 1991-1992 (Box 11, Folder 123-124)
  - Beyond the Paradigm of Conflict, 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 125)
  - Private Action/Public Good: Maryland's Nonprofit Sector in a Time of Change, 1997-1998 (Box 11, Folder 126-129, Box 12, Folder 130-134)
  - Maryland Nonprofit Survey: 1995, 1988-1996 (Box 13, Folder 135)
  - President's Reorganization Project: Local Development Assistance, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 136)
  - The Nonprofit Sector in an Era of Retrenchment, 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 137-139)
  - Civil Society Futures Project, 1996-1998 (Box 14, Folder 140-141)
  - Decentralizing the Policy: Lessons from American Experience, Volume 1, Part 1: Public Finance and Intergovernmental Relations, undated (Box 14, Folder 142)
  - Decentralizing the Policy: Lessons from American Experience, Volume 2, Part 2: Environmental Land Use Planning, Part 3: Economic Development, undated (Box 14, Folder 143)
  - The Federal Government and Nonprofit Sector: Implications of the Reagan Budget Revisions, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 144-146)
  - Block Grants and the Rise of Third Party Government: The Challenge to Public Management, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 147-148)
  - Government and the Nonprofit Sector: An Agenda for Research, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 149)
  - The Illusion on Presidential Government, 1981-1987 (Box 15, Folder 150)
  - Federal Government and Nonprofit Sector: Implications of Reagan Budget Proposals, 1981-1982 (Box 16, Folder 151-153)
  - Research Agenda: Tools of Government Action, Public Management Program, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 154)
  - The Presidency and Nonprofit Policy the Changing Context: Interdependence, Third-Party Government, and New Pluralism, 1979-1980 (Box 16, Folder 155)
  - In Pursuit of Reorganization: The Question of Goals, 1980-1981 (Box 16, Folder 156-157)
  - The Impact of the 1981 Tax Act on Individual Charitable Giving, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 158-159)
  - The Budget's Mid-Life Crisis, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 160)
  - Rethinking Public Management: The Changing Forms of Government Action, 1980-1981 (Box 17, Folder 161-162)
  - The Stakes in Regulatory Reform: A Political Analysis, 1980-1981 (Box 18, Folder 163)
  - Child-Serving Nonprofit Organizations in an Era of Government Retrenchment: A Report for the Foundation for Child Development, undated (Box 18, Folder 164)
  - Nonprofits: The Results Are Coming In, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 165)
  - Human Services Spending in Rhode Island: The Changing Roles of Government and Private Funders, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 166)
  - Human Services Spending in Boise: The Changing Roles of Government and Private Funders, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 167)
  - Human Services Spending in Phoenix and Pinal County: The Changing Roles of Government and Private Funders, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 168)
  - Human Service Spending in Dallas: The Changing Roles of Government and Private Funders, undated (Box 18, Folder 169)
  - Government Spending and the Nonprofit Sector in Allegheny County/Pittsburgh, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 170)
  - Providing Human Services in Chicago: Government and Nonprofit Organizations, undated (Box 18, Folder 171)
  - The Twin Cities Nonprofit Sector in a Time of Government Retrenchment, undated (Box 18, Folder 172)
  - Partners in Public Service: Government and the Nonprofit Sector in Rhode Island, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 173)
  - Government and the Nonprofit Sector, The Economic Competitiveness of Maryland: Preface, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 174)
  - More than Just Charity: The Baltimore Area Nonprofit Sector in a Time of Change, 1989-1994 (Box 19, Folder 175-178, Box 20, Folder 179-180)
  - Baltimore Nonprofits, 1987-1989 (Box 20, Folder 181-184)
  - Some Lessons for Baltimore from Bologna, 1988-1989 (Box 21, Folder 185)
  - Nonprofit Organizations and the FY 1990 Federal Budget, 1989-1990 (Box 21, Folder 186)
  - Gutowski Draft, National Survey Book, undated (Box 21, Folder 187)
  - De Toqueville Revisite, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 188)
  - The Nonprofit Sector and Government: The American Experience in Theory and Practice, 1988-1989 (Box 21, Folder 189)
  - NAPA and the Management of Privatization, 1987-1989 (Box 21, Folder 190-192, Box 22, Folder 193-194)
  - The Voluntary Sector and the Future of the Welfare State, 1989-1991 (Box 22, Folder 195-196)